I am an education researcher with over ten years' experience in project coordination and supervision, as well as data management, analysis, and reporting. I am happiest working at the intersection of K-12 education research and data management, helping researchers and practitioners obtain insights that improve student outcomes through harmonized, reliable, and documented data. I am also passionate about helping others organize their data and reporting through reproducible workflows.

Technical Skills_

R, SPSS, Qualtrics, Stata, Microsoft Access, Quick Base, SQL, Git and GitHub, Tableau, SAS, SharePoint

Education

University of Minnesota Minneapolis, MN

MASTER OF PUBLIC POLICY 2009-2011

• Concentration: Advanced Policy Analysis

University of Missouri

Columbia, MO **BACHELOR OF SOCIAL WORK** 2001-2005

· Concentration: Research Methods

Experience_

Freelance Remote

DATA MANAGEMENT CONSULTANT

Mar 2022 - Present

· Providing research data management consulting, training, and data wrangling services to improve organizational workflows.

Streamline Data Science

Remote

DATA SCIENTIST Nov 2021 - Mar 2022

- Built example client facing crm dashboard in R flexdashboard to be used to publicize services. Currently featured on Streamline's
- Ingested data sources to build an internal metric tracking R flexdashboard that is automated through Google Cloud Platform to update daily. The dashboard is used regularly by the sales team.
- Built google trends R flexdashboard to show capabilities of automatic updating data.

Missouri Prevention Science Institute

University of Missouri

DIRECTOR OF DATA STRATEGY

May 2019 - Nov 2021

- Strategized data management plans for over ten actively funded projects and oversee their implementation.
- Merged, cleaned, manipulated, gueried, and documented data collected from school districts, state education agencies, surveys, assessments, and observations using R.
- Built reports, dashboards, and visualizations for dissemination of data.

DIRECTOR OF RESEARCH IMPLEMENTATION

Jul 2016-May 2019

- Supervised successful completion of data collection activities for six federally funded randomized controlled trial studies and two county funded projects.
- Delivered quarterly trainings to staff on data collection methods.
- Designed and built data collection tools including Qualtrics surveys and Access tracking databases.

Aug 2013 - Jul 2016 RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

- Coordinated two Institute of Education Sciences funded randomized controlled trial studies.
- Collected data in schools through classroom observations, surveys, and assessments.
- Established trusting relationships with school district partners.

Big Brothers Big Sisters of Eastern Missouri

St. Louis, MO

EVALUATION AND OUTCOMES MANAGER

Jun 2011 - Aug 2013

· Oversaw the collection, analysis, and dissemination of data relating to performance management, outcomes, and customer satisfaction.

May 2022 1

Center for Advanced Studies in Child Welfare

University of Minnesota

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jan 2010 - Jul 2011

• Evaluated the effectiveness of the Hennepin County Attorney's Office truancy intervention program using qualitative and quantitative methods.

Humphrey School of Public Affairs

University of Minnesota

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Aug 2010 - Dec 2010

• Taught lab sessions of a graduate level introductory statistics course using Stata.

Hennepin-University Partnership

University of Minnesota

GRADUATE ASSISTANT

Sep 2009 - May 2010

• Connected County officials with University faculty to develop effective partnerships to improve the community.

Service

POWER Issues in Data Management in Education Research Hub

Remote

Organizer

Jan 2022 - Present

• Organize and host monthly meetups and presentations on data management topics

R-Ladies St. Louis

St. Louis, MO Aug 2020 - Present

Co-organizerOrganize and host monthly workshops

LaunchCode

St. Louis, MO

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Jan 2018 - July 2018

• Developed curriculum and taught data analysis once a week for a cohort of 25 women looking to make a career transition.

AmeriCorps St. Louis Education Team

St. Louis, MO

TEAM LEAD

Aug 2007 - Aug 2008

• Tutored elementary students, led educational programming, and supervised a team of three tutors

Data Manager for the Following Grants.

Boone County Children Services Fund: The FACE of Boone County, PI: Aaron Thompson, (2020-2024)

Institute of Education Sciences: Efficacy study of Discipline in the Secondary Classroom, PI: Carl Sumi, (2018-2023) (R305A170040)

National Institute of Justice: Evaluation of a principal training program to promote safe & civil schools, PI: Keith Herman, (2017-2021) (2016-CK-BX-0004)

Institute of Education Sciences: Evaluation of a training program to promote effective school leadership, PI: Keith Herman, (2017-2022) (R305A170180)

Institute of Education Sciences: Implementing a comprehensive data-based coordinated System of care for school districts to promote youth academic success and social emotional development: A researcher-practitioner partnership, PI: Wendy Reinke, (2017-2019)

Institute of Education Sciences: Evaluation of a self-monitoring training program for elementary school students, PI: Aaron Thompson, (2015-2019) (R305A150517)

Boone County Children's Services Fund: Boone County Mental Health Coalition County-wide Initiative to Support School-age Youth, PI: Wendy Reinke, (2014-2020).

Institute of Education Sciences: The Classroom Check-Up: Supporting teachers in classroom management using a web-based coaching system, PI: Wendy Reinke, (2013–2018) (R305A130375)

Institute of Education Sciences: Evaluation of a classroom management training program for middle school teachers, PI: Keith Herman, (2013–2018) (R305A130143)

Institute of Education Sciences: Evaluation of a Video-based Modeling Program to Promote Effective Teacher Classroom Management Practices, PI: Wendy Reinke, (2010-2015) (R305A100342)

Publications

May 2022 2

Cohen, D., Lewis, C.G., Eddy, C.L., Henry, L., Hodgson, C. & Huang, F.L. (2021) In-School and Out-of-School Suspension: Behavioral and Psychological Outcomes in a Predominately Black Sample of Middle School Students. School Psychology Review, DOI: 10.1080/2372966X.2020.1856628

Henry, L., Reinke, W.M., Herman, K.C., Thompson, A.M. & Lewis, C.G. (2020) Motivational interviewing with at-risk students (MARS) mentoring: Addressing the unique mental health needs of students in alternative school placements, School Psychology Review, 50:1, 62-74.

Huang, F., Lewis, C., Cohen, D., Prewett, S., & Herman, K. (2018). Bullying involvement, teacher-student relationships, and psychosocial outcomes. School Psychology Quarterly, 33(2), 223-234.

Lewis, C.G., Herman, K.C., Huang, F.L., Stormont, M., Grossman, C., Eddy, C., & Reinke, W.M. (2017). The utility of single-item readiness screeners in middle school. Journal of School Psychology. 64, 1–16.

Larson, A., Singh, S. & Lewis, C. (2011). Sanctions and Education Outcomes for Children in TANF Families, Child and Youth Services, 32:3, 180-199.

Presentations

Lewis, C. (2021). Data Management in Large-Scale Education Research. Series of workshops given for Missouri Prevention Science Institute, University of Missouri, Columbia, MO.

Lewis, C. (2019). Cleaning Messy Data in R. Presented at R-Ladies St. Louis Meetup, Washington University in St. Louis.

Lewis, C. (2019). Introduction to R. Guest lecture for LaunchCode CoderGirl Data Analysis track, St. Louis, MO.

Lewis, C. (2018). Survey Says: You can use Tableau to Impact School Climate. Presented at Tableau Fringe Festival APAC, Online.

May 2022 3